Guide to the Mitchell Kennerley Papers, 1898-1984
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Mitchell Kennerley Papers
1898-1984
Kennerley, Mitchell, 1878-1950
1 cubic foot (3 boxes)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Correspondence, contracts, printed ephemera, and other materials from publisher Mitchell Kennerley that document his work on behalf of writers, including Randolph G. Adams, Zoe Atkins, Arnold Bennett, Dorothy Beall Cunningham, Bliss Carman, Max Eastman, Frank Harris, Alfred A. Knopf, D.H. Lawrence, Christopher Morley, and Edna St. Vincent Millay.
Biographical Note
Mitchell Kennerley (1878-1950) was an American publisher and art dealer.
Scope and Content Note
Correspondence, contracts, reports, photographs, and printed materials from Mitchell Kennerley's work on behalf of writers including Randolph G. Adams, Zoe Atkins, Arnold Bennett, Dorothy Beall Cunningham, Bliss Carman, Max Eastman, Frank Harris, Alfred A. Knopf, D.H. Lawrence, Christopher Morley, and Edna St. Vincent Millay.
Access
This collection is open for research according to the
regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library
without any additional restrictions.
Related Materials
Mitchell Kennerley Rare Books Collection, Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College
Subject Headings
Names:
Adams, Randolph Greenfield, 1864-1950; Atkins, Zoe; Bennett, Arnold, 1867-1931; Cunningham, Dorothy Beall; Carman, Bliss, 1861-1929; Eastman, Max, 1883-1969; Harris, Frank, 1855-1931; Knopf, Alfred A., 1892-1984; Lawrence, D. H. (David Herbert), 1885-1930; Morley, Christopher, 1890-1957; Millay, Edna St. Vincent, 1892-1950
Subjects:
Authors; Women authors, American
Document Types:
Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence; Photographs; Printed ephemera
VCL Categories:
Literature and Writing; Printing and Publishing
Encoding Information
Encoded by Elizabeth Clarke, April 2007. Updated by Emma Gronbeck, July 2024.
Container List
- Correspondence
  - Adams, Randolph G. to Kennerley, 1934 (Folder 1.1)
  - Bennett, Arnold to and from Kennerley, 1926 (Folder 1.2)
  - Blount, L.E. to Kennerley, with clipping, 1917 (Folder 1.3)
  - Borden, Fanny to and from Kennerley, 1930-1950 (Folders 1.4-1.8)
  - Borden, Fanny from miscellaneous, re: Kennerley, 1930-1931 (Folder 1.9)
  - Bynner, Witter ("Hal") to Kennerley, 1914 (Folder 1.10)
  - Carman, Bliss to Kennerley, 1898-1929, undated (Folders 1.11-1.15)
  - Carter, John to Kennerley, 1934 (Folder 1.16)
  - Cunningham, Dorothy Beall to Kennerley, 1932 (Folder 1.17)
  - Gracie, Archibald to Kennerley, 1912 (Folder 1.18)
  - Harvey, Alexander to Kennerley, 1923 (Folder 1.19)
  - Harris, Frank to Kennerley, 1901-1909 (Folder 1.20)
  - Hergesheimer, Joseph to Kennerley, 1914-1915 (Folder 1.21)
  - Jefferson, Allan A. to Kennerley, 1929 (Folder 1.22)
  - Kemp, Harry to Kennerley, undated (Folder 1.23)
  - Lanza, Clara to Kennerley, 1925 (Folder 1.24)
  - Lawrence, D.H. to Kennerley, 1913 (Folder 1.25)
  - Lee, Gerald Stanley to Kennerley, 1918 (Folder 1.26)
  - McArthur, Peter to Kennerley, 1920 (Folder 1.27)
  - Melville, John to Kennerley, 1932 Jan 3 (Folder 1.28)
  - Miscellaneous to Kennerley, re: Donald Lowrie, 1925 (Folder 1.29)
  - Morley, Christopher to Kennerley, 1922-1933, undated (Folder 1.30)
  - Neihardt, John G. to Kennerley, 1909 (Folder 1.31)
  - Nirdlinger, Charles to Kennerley, undated (Folder 1.32)
  - Noguchi, Yone to Kennerley, undated (Folder 1.33)
  - Pierce, Lorne to Kennerley, 1928-1932, undated (Folder 1.34)
  - Wagstaff, Blanche Shoemaker to Kennerley, undated (Folder 1.35)
- Writings, Printed Ephemera, and Other Material
  - Articles about Kennerley, 1929-1984 (Folder 1.36)
  - Autograph - Ficke, Arthur Davison, undated (Folder 1.37)
  - Book prospectuses, 1915-1937, undated (Folder 1.38)
  - Card catalog - Kennerley publications, undated (Folder 2.1)
  - Checklists of Kennerley publications, 1906-1938 (Folders 2.2-2.3)
  - Clippings and printed ephemera - By and about Kennerley, 1931-1940 (Folder 2.4)
  - Clippings and printed ephemera - By and about Others, 1905-1935 (Folder 2.5)
  - Miscellaneous letters, leaflets, and photographs removed from the Kennerley Book Collection, 1912-1939 (Folder 2.6)
  - Pamphlets, 1919-1932 (Folder 3.1)
  - Photographs, 1930, undated (Folder 2.7)
  - Publishing contracts, A-G (by author's name), 1909-1918 (Folder 3.2)
  - Publishing contracts, H-V (by author's name), 1906-1915 (Folder 3.3)
  - "Publishing - Old and New" by Lewis Mumford (The New Republic), 1930 Oct 1 (Folder 3.4)
  - Reader's Reports by Arthur Hooley (Charles Vale), 1908-1924 (Folders 2.8-2.14)